= kisskh.asia =
=Against The Current=
(Adapted from He Yanshan's novel, Orchid Fragrance Fate)
=Episode 18= (This drama does not correspond)
(to any real historical dynasty.)
(The systems, culture, attire and other dynastic elements have been adapted.)
Young Master!
Watch out!
Cuique.
Don't be afraid.
Let Yinchen and Wei
take you to Aunt Shunhua's Rongzhang House.
Once the imperial physician arrives,
you'll get better.
Don't worry about me.
I'm staying with First Madam and Xiushu.
First Madam's household authority tokens and seal
are all here.
As for this matter,
Lanxiang, you handle it.
Du Cuique,
hand over the antidote.
What are you talking about?
I don't understand.
Aren't you curious
how you were poisoned?
Even if I've acted improperly in the past
and offended you,
look at the state I'm in now.
I'm already pitiful enough.
Lanxiang,
why must you
make things harder for someone in my condition?
You must have guessed
there was something wrong with the tea you drank earlier.
But do you know where
the poison in the tea came from?
Last night,
Young Master didn't bathe at all
before going out.
The water used to make your tea
was the hot water you prepared for Young Master.
Baogai reheated it and made tea with it.
Gantang served it right back to you.
You thought Young Master had already fallen ill and lost consciousness.
You thought if you could just hold out a little longer,
someone would come to save you.
Young Lady Du,
I'm sorry
to disappoint you.
Young Master is perfectly well and out there right now.
He may even be dealing with
the benefactor who gave you the Yunzi stones and Xinggu gauze.
You...
You're wondering how I know
and how much I know?
When you were bent on climbing higher,
you never bothered to look down.
But everything you eat, wear, and use
passes through the hands of
lowly maids like us.
We saw it all.
You had Lingdang poison the hot water.
Tongcao saw it.
You accepted the Yunzi stones.
Xiaolian saw it.
You wore an undershirt made of Xinggu gauze.
Gantang saw it.
Xiuwan!
Zheng saved Jinqi's life.
Cuique is an honored guest of our Lin Residence.
You lowly maid, how dare you spout such nonsense
and make these vicious accusations!
I'll slap that mouth of yours bloody!
Xiuwan.
They're not good people at all.
I saw it.
The cave beneath Enduring the Cold Pavilion.
You helped Du Cuique.
What is she to you?
Did you ever think about us?
If you do that,
what will happen to Xiushu and me?
What about our eldest sister?
Xiuwan.
Jinqiao.
Go bring your sister back.
To create the illusion of an epidemic,
you always administered the poison through the bathwater.
But when you realized
I suspected you,
you killed Lingdang.
If I'm right,
the poison you gave Lingdang
was put in her food.
She ate it without suspecting a thing.
Lanxiang.
I simply did the same
and made tea with the water
you poisoned for you to drink.
You want to outlast First Madam,
but can you?
First Madam didn't ingest the poison.
Du Cuique,
you're exceptionally talented and meticulous.
What a brilliant strategist you are.
Now that it's come to this,
why lose your dignity by denying it?
Congyi saved Jinqi's life.
As long as you hand over the antidote
and everyone is safe,
I promise the Lin family won't pursue the matter.
We'll consider your lifesaving favor repaid.
That's right.
This isn't an illness.
It's poison.
I poisoned them.
The antidote?
I don't have it.
I never expected to be poisoned myself.
Why would I prepare an antidote?
However,
I do have the formula for the antidote.
Hand over the formula.
What do you take me for?
Some petty thief?
You think poisoning me
will frighten me out of my wits
and force me to hand over the antidote to save my life?
Xu Lanxiang,
you've misjudged me.
Since I chose this path,
I was never afraid.
I'm not afraid to take another's life,
much less have someone take mine.
You need the antidote,
so you didn't dare give me a heavy dose
in case I died like Lingdang.
No matter how desperate I become,
that Yuchan
will die before I do.
But Yuchan has no grievance with me.
I never intended to kill her.
The one I wanted dead
was you.
She
is dying in your place.
That wretched old woman Qin
looked down on me, didn't she?
Fine.
Then she can die with her daughter and keep me company.
Even if Lin Jinqi is alive,
what difference does it make?
He caused his mother's death
and his sister's death.
For the rest of his life,
does he think he'll ever live in peace?
What are you after?
What am I after?
How could the small-minded understand great ambitions?
With so many people in the Lin Residence
dying along with me,
I'd say it's worth it.
But Xu Lanxiang,
remember this.
You're the one who poisoned me.
That's why they won't get the antidote.
They
will all die because of you.
You're wrong.
I saved them.
The only person you can poison to death
is yourself.
- First Madam!
Thanks to Lanxiang,
we got the antidote.
Concubine Zhou and I were only mildly poisoned.
We recovered after taking the antidote.
The others were more severely poisoned.
They'll need some time to recuperate,
but they're all out of danger now.
How...
How can this be?
Impossible.
Last night,
Lanxiang had Nanke take the poisoned water
to the Imperial Medical Service.
Your poisoning method may be devious
and based on a secret technique from the southern borderlands,
but this is Jinling, the Southern Capital,
where skilled experts abound.
The Imperial Medical Service even has a physician from Yunnan Prefecture.
Once they had a sample of your poison,
how could they fail to formulate an antidote?
Right now,
they're busy treating the patients in Fengqi Courtyard.
Later,
they'd also like to compare notes with you.
Please apologize to the imperial physicians
on my behalf.
I'm afraid I'll have to leave first.
I won't have time to speak with them.
Ever since you entered this residence,
I've never treated you unfairly.
Even though I didn't want you to become Jinqi's concubine,
I still looked everywhere for a well-off family for you
and tried to arrange a good marriage for you.
Why do you
hate our Lin family so much?
A well-off family?
A good marriage?
Let me guess.
It would probably be
a farming family with some land of their own.
A family like that
would have struggled to put one son through his studies.
He couldn't marry a proper young lady from a prominent family,
but then along comes someone like me,
someone with ties to the Lin Residence.
Once I married into the family,
I'd have to manage the household,
be a dutiful daughter-in-law,
bear and raise children, get along with my sisters-in-law,
and use my ties to the Lin Residence
to help my husband build connections.
I might even
have to spend my entire dowry
to help my husband rise through the ranks.
This is
what you call a good marriage?
What's wrong with that?
Don't you want your husband to rise in rank and become an official?
If I want wealth and status,
why would I marry into a family like that?
Am I out of my mind?
I'd bring my dowry with me
only to work myself to the bone for them.
If I have to marry anyway,
I'll marry into a wealthy and powerful family.
If the Lin family won't accept me,
another prominent family will.
Water flows downward, while people strive to rise.
There's nothing wrong with wanting
success, wealth, and status.
But you shouldn't resort to underhanded means!
Then let me ask you, First Madam,
what other open road is there
for someone like me?
My talent and learning are no less than any man's.
But can I take the imperial examination and become the top scholar?
Or can I join the army and win a noble title through battle?
Other than marriage,
what other path has this world
left for a woman like me?
Haven't you simply decided
that marrying me off well
would repay my brother for saving Jinqi's life?
What's wrong with getting married?
What else can a woman do
if she doesn't marry?
How pitiful.
How truly pitiful.
You really are pitiful.
What are you laughing at?
What's so wrong with getting married?
What's so pitiful about it?
A woman was born amid the chaos of the previous dynasty.
At twelve or thirteen, she was sold as a child bride.
Unable to endure her in-laws' abuse,
she ran away
and eventually ended up in Yazhou.
But she never gave up on herself.
She learned weaving from the local women
and worked hard to support herself.
A woman like that
would drift aimlessly
or live a life of drudgery.
After she passed away,
cotton became widely cultivated.
The local women,
using the techniques she had taught them,
wove Songjiang cloth that became renowned throughout the land.
In Songjiang Prefecture,
the people built a shrine to honor her,
and offerings have never ceased.
A woman
could be revered like a sage,
her name remembered in history...
Offerings...
Offerings at a shrine?
Her name was Huang Daopo.
Perhaps you've never heard of her,
but you've certainly used
the Songjiang cloth she passed down.
Her divine titles, the Weaver Star and First Deity of Cotton,
are ones you've surely worshiped, too.
Lanxiang is right.
Du Cuique,
don't blame everything on an unjust world.
No matter how unjust the world may be,
you still have to live with honor and integrity.
You're simply consumed by greed
and want everything without working for it.
♪ If there were a promise ♪
Wei.
Give her the antidote.
We can't let her die like this in the Lin Residence.
I won't drink it.
I don't want it.
I won't take the medicine!
I won't drink it!
Let me die!
No!
I won't drink it!
♪ Memories hide away again ♪
♪ Silent, yet they never stop shining ♪
♪ Still burning bright ♪
Take her away.
Hand her over to the authorities.
Xu Lanxiang!
Even as a ghost, I'll never let you go!
I'll never let you go!
Xu Lanxiang!
Even as a ghost, I'll never let you go!
First Madam.
Yuchan, Xiaolian, Madam Wu, and the others
are really all right?
Don't worry.
The imperial physicians arrived in time.
They're all fine.
We helped, too.
(Prison)
Move.
Forgive us, Registrar Dai.
Behave yourself.
Why?
♪ Every word carries countless thoughts ♪
♪ The encounters of half a lifetime are kept within this little world ♪
♪ Bit by bit, the passing years become the preface ♪
♪ The joys and sorrows of the past quietly dwell here ♪
Congyi.
♪ With my own hands and heart ♪
♪ I write my name ♪
♪ Through countless lines of ink, step by step toward the light ♪
Commander Yuan's archery
is renowned.
A single arrow struck a vital spot.
His internal organs are damaged and bleeding.
I can only tend to his wound
and apply some pain-relieving powder
to ease his pain a little.
Thank you, Imperial Physician Zhou.
Congyi.
Cuique...
Did Cuique
succeed?
The Lin...
The Lin family
is dead...
Assistant Commander Lin.
Thank you for your efforts.
Take good care of him.
Rest assured, Assistant Commander Lin.
I'll see that he's well cared for.
Have a drink!
Let's all have a drink!
Drink up!
- Have a drink!
Drink up.
Come on.
Fill everyone's cup.
Baogai.
You did a great service.
You should eat more.
Gantang did a great service, too.
Gantang, you should eat more, too.
I can't drink anymore.
If I drink any more, it'll interfere with tomorrow's work.
Everyone.
First Madam said
this banquet today
is a reward for us.
We can drink as much as we like.
Even I'm not afraid.
What are you afraid of?
Have a drink.
- Cheers!
- A toast to First Madam.
- Thank you for the reward.
Come on.
Here.
Fill them up.
This is fine liquor from First Madam.
Don't waste it. Fill them up.
Fill them up.
- Come on, drink up!
- Drink up!
Lanxiang deserves the most credit. You should eat more today.
Let's have another drink.
Lanxiang, let's have another drink together.
Come on, hurry.
Pour Lanxiang another cup.
Tongcao is out of liquor, too.
Go get another flask.
I'll go.
Come on.
Fill them up.
Don't just drink. Have something to eat, too.
I can't drink anymore. I really can't.
I should toast you, too.
I can't.
Yuchan said her life
was saved by Lanxiang, Baogai, Gantang,
and Tongcao.
Unfortunately, she still needs bed rest,
so she asked me to make sure I
have a few drinks with all of you on her behalf tonight.
Gantang.
Young Master.
Yuchan is all right now!
We should drink more to Lanxiang. She deserves the most credit.
Right.
I'll drink three full bowls with Lanxiang.
That's right, Lanxiang.
You two stay here.
Look who's here.
Hua.
You should drink three full cups with Jiugao on Yuchan's behalf.
These past few days,
he's been running around
and helping us a great deal.
And Nanke, too.
Everyone should drink three full cups with him.
Thanks to him sneaking in without anyone noticing
and then sneaking back out the same way.
Come on. Let's each go drink three full cups with them.
All right. Let's go.
Bring the liquor flasks.
All right.
Let's go.
Off we go.
Careful.
Go have a good drink with Jiugao and Nanke.
Hurry and catch up.
Hurry.
Nanke! Jiugao!
We're here to toast you!
Come on, fill them up.
The cups.
I want to toast you, too.
- Nanke!
I'll pour for you.
One at a time.
We'll each toast you once.
Nanke deserves much of the credit.
All of us
should toast him first.
All right.
Drink!
This time,
it's all thanks to you.
I'll always remember it
and never forget.
I'll drink first as a sign of respect.
That's my cup.
So?
What?
You'll drink when Yinchen and the others toast you,
but when I toast you,
you won't drink?
How about.
I call Yinchen and the others back
and have each of them toast you with a full cup?
Yin...
You're playing dirty.
One more cup.
Drink.
I can't drink anymore.
I
have to get out of here.
♪ Look at us ♪
♪ We've shared countless beautiful moments ♪
♪ Through life's winding road, we've weathered countless trials ♪
♪ I'm blessed to spend each peaceful day and night with you ♪
♪ However deep the joy or sorrow ♪
♪ There will always be someone to share it with ♪
♪ Our bond runs deep ♪
♪ Binding us closely together ♪
♪ Washing away the dust of this mortal world ♪
♪ Even if we must part in the end ♪
♪ I'll have no regrets that we met in this life ♪
♪ May we stay together until life's end ♪
♪ Every sincerity you've shown me ♪
♪ Has long taken root in my heart ♪
♪ Our bond runs deep ♪
♪ Binding us closely together ♪
♪ After all the questions life has brought ♪
♪ This love has never faded in the slightest ♪
♪ A trace of fragrance lingers on ♪
It smells wonderful.
♪ How fortunate to find one person in a lifetime ♪
What flower is that fragrance from?
♪ My heart remains as true to you as ever ♪
Orchids.
Some orchids are most fragrant at noon.
Other orchids
are most fragrant at night.
What are you doing?
I want to smell the flowers.
Which do you like better,
the fragrance of flowers or silver?
Silver.
You're not too drunk to think straight.
It's good to be alive.
I can still smell the flowers.
Congyi...
Du Zheng is dying.
Du Cuique must think.
I caused her brother's death.
I wanted to repay them.
I had Du Zheng transferred to Jinling
and brought Du Cuique into the residence.
Was I wrong?
You did nothing wrong.
They were the ones in the wrong.
They were too greedy.
In this world,
who doesn't want a better life?
I'm greedy, too.
But our forebears taught us,
"A gentleman acquires wealth by honorable means."
You can't trample on others
just because you want a better life.
I don't think I did anything wrong, either.
But why
do I still feel so awful?
Because
you
are a good person.
♪ If you're a lone traveler returning through the snow ♪
I'm a good person...
♪ If you're the silent fragrance of a secluded orchid ♪
I like hearing that.
Say it some more...
♪ Deep within the lights lies a truth that came too late ♪
♪ Even if these trials consume my whole life ♪
You're really drunk.
♪ I'll only return to the moment our fate began ♪
♪ I've searched and searched, wandering in circles ♪
♪ Yet I can never mend that old dream ♪
♪ Leaving only regret behind ♪
♪ Thankfully, these trials have spared me a lifetime ♪
♪ In this life and the next, it will always be you ♪
♪ I only pray that fate lets us meet sooner ♪
(Your pay and provisions come from the people's toil.)
Liang Yu, Commander of the Shence Garrison,
has enjoyed His Majesty's favor,
yet gave no thought to serving the realm.
He colluded with Dai Rong
and formed a faction for personal gain.
He disregarded the greater good
and pursued his own interests.
He is hereby stripped of office and imprisoned.
=Against the Current= (Next Episode's Preview)
First Madam, Young Master, for all you've done for us,
our whole family will always remember your kindness.
Every day, we'll kowtow to the Bodhisattva
and pray for the Bodhisattva's blessings.
May First Madam be blessed with many descendants
and an ever-flourishing family line.
May Young Master be blessed with a destined match
and a marriage made in heaven.
Yes.
Every day, we'll kowtow and burn incense to the Bodhisattva
and pray for the Bodhisattva's blessings.
May...
May the Bodhisattva bless you.
You certainly have a way with words.
What you said
is exactly what First Madam and I wish for.
May your auspicious words come true.
I hope that someday,
everything will turn out just as we wish.
♪ Spring slips from the branches once more ♪
♪ Flowers bloom unseen, as they have before ♪
♪ All the joys and sorrows come and go ♪
♪ While loss leaves winter in the heart ♪
♪ Though all the world may fade ♪
♪ Time rolls on as countless lives rush by ♪
♪ Night winds wander through the halls of long ago ♪
♪ No page could hold the longing words can never show ♪
♪ Every joy and sorrow in this fleeting life ♪
♪ Fades into the past as new wounds rise ♪
♪ While whispers of perfume linger beneath the eaves ♪
♪ Let the cold wind rage, let the wild rain fall ♪
♪ Let sorrow spill like shadows over all ♪
♪ Let love fall to pieces, let old anger burn away ♪
♪ Let the past die with yesterday ♪
♪ One last fire, one last cup of wine ♪
♪ And silver moonlight to guide me through the night ♪
♪ Let beginnings fade as endings come to call ♪
♪ From this endless dream, there's no return at all ♪
♪ Let the cold wind rage, let the wild rain fall ♪
♪ Let sorrow spill like shadows over all ♪
♪ Let love fall to pieces, let old anger burn away ♪
♪ Let the past die with yesterday ♪
♪ One last fire, one last cup of wine ♪
♪ And silver moonlight to guide me through the night ♪
♪ Let beginnings fade as endings come to call ♪
♪ From this endless dream, there's no return at all ♪